TAMUNO-OMI JAJA

No. 68 Woji Estate Road, Port Harcourt, NIGERIA. https://www.linkedin.com/in/tamjaja/ Tamuno-omi (Tamuno-omi Jaja) (github.com)

Tel: +234 813-126-8008

PROFILE

A resourceful and result oriented computer scientist with professional experience on telecommunications engineering technologies and networks, multi-vendor systems integrations and configurations, Microwave transmission systems, TCP/ IP networks and Data analysis with an unwavering work ethic and strong passion to improve my professional skills and add value to any establishment that engages my expertise.

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

2019 – Present MSc. Computer Science (In view)

University of Port Harcourt, NIGERIA.

2011 – 2015 **BSc. Computer Science**

University of Port Harcourt, NIGERIA.

2005 – 2011 O-Levels (Nine S.S.C.E subjects passed including English Language & Mathematics)

Nigerian Airforce Secondary School, Port Harcourt, NIGERIA.

SKILLS

Programming: Java, HTML, CSS, XML, Python

Applications: Microsoft Office 365 applications including Microsoft Outlook, Office Online,

SharePoint, Teams, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Visio, OneNote, Microsoft PowerPoint.,

Adobe Illustrator, Android Studio, Aviat Eclipse Portal, Wip Manage for Airspan, Power

Bi.

Database: Sql.

Networking: Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA), Routing and Switching, Cisco Certified

Network Professional (CCNP), Routing & Switching (CCNP), Huawei Certified ICT

Associate (HCIA) - Routing and Switching

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS AND COURSES

August 2016	Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) - Routing and Switching.
January 2019	Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNP) - Routing and Switching
0-4-12010	One de Detales a COL Contide d'Accessor

October 2018 Oracle Database SQL Certified Associate.

March 2019 Tropical Helicopter Underwater Escape Training (HUET)

April 2020 Udacity Data Science Nanodegree

August 2021 Huawei Certified ICT Associate (HCIA) - Routing and Switching

February 2022 Udacity SQL Nanodegree

TECHNICAL SKILLS SUMMARY

- Good Knowledge and work experience on TETRA radio system
- Aviat Networks Eclipse radio series systems configuration, installations, link commissioning, administration, and maintenance.

- Routine availability monitoring and reporting of offshore telecom infrastructure for remote fault diagnosis and resolution.
- Use of RF and Microwave test and troubleshooting equipment which include Spectrum analyser and RF power meters.
- Excellent knowledge and hand-on experience working on Cisco Catalyst series network Switches and Routers, configurations and deployments for LAN and WAN architecture, multi-vendor system's and equipment integrations, configurations, installations.
- Management of TEPNG billing and fraud management system for TEPNG desk and mobile phone subscribers.
- ❖ Data Analysis and taxation reporting of TEPNG telecoms service subscribers.
- Good operating knowledge of Windows Server 2003, Windows 2000, Windows XP, Windows Vista, Windows 7 and Java, HTML, CSS, XML s
- ❖ Good verbal and written communication skills.
- Proficient in the use of Microsoft Office suites which includes MS Word, Excel, Project, PowerPoint, and Visio.
- * Result oriented and a self starter, always eager to take on new and bigger challenges.
- Good team player with demonstrable ability to lead and instil confidence to achieve team goals as well as working independently under pressure without supervision.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

IT systems Engineer:

January 2022 - till date

Nexus Alliance Limited(http://www.nexusallianceltd.com/)

- ❖ Supervised IT INFRASTURE at Total Village Port Harcourt
- Provided IT support remotely and physically to residences and personnel
- Used Service now ticketing systems to manage and process support actions and requests
- Managed the task and performance of third-party contractors working for Telecoms department at Total Village.
- Created support documentation to empower and enable user community to extend skills, leverage system features and find resolutions to questions without intervention from the support team.
- ❖ IT assets allocation and inventory management- Handle the consistency and integrity of records saved in the asset management software.
- Resolved escalations from the helpdesk support team.

IT Systems Engineer & Data Analyst:

February 2018 – December 2021.

Philips Project Centre (PPC) Ltd, Port Harcourt, NIGERIA (www.ppcng.com)

- Maintained Terrestrial Trunk Radio (TETRA) Network, which included setting up of new users and repairing of faulty Tetra radio equipment for TEPNG.
- Installed, configured, and supported network equipment including routers, proxy servers, switches, WAN accelerators, DNS and DHCP at TEPNG Village

- Maintained Joint Venture Microwave Radio links (Airspan & Aviat Eclipse), which included setting up and troubleshooting of microwave radio products.
- Ensured availability of offshore telecom infrastructure through remote monitoring, trouble shooting, fault resolution and reporting.
- Managed of TEPNG Network billing and fraud management system for desk and mobile phone subscribers.
- Produced taxation and Trend analysis reports for management decision and budgeting.
- Managed TEPNG Telephony database.
- Prepared of weekly and monthly systems and network status / performance reports for presentation to TEPNG management.
- Set up and managed workstations at TEPNG Air Village
- ❖ Managed IT equipment store at TEPNG Air Village and ensured that inventories were up to date.
- * Resolved connectivity issues for workstations, IPTV, Network printers, Wireless Access points and IP phones.
- ❖ Assisted in training personnel at TEPNG Air Village on new software which included office 365 applications

SHELL PETROLEUM DEVELOPMENT COMPANY,

INDUSTRIAL TRAINEE | June 2014 - December 2014

- Participated in Shell Petroleum Development Company of Nigeria Ltd (SPDC) telephony network and billing system maintenance project.
- Resolution of technical network issues using variety of diagnostic tools such as LAN cable testers, Network Analyzer (wire shack)
- Implementation of Structured Office Cabling (SOC) for LAN connectivity and assisting users in the resolution of computer related faults

AWARDS:

Top 3 finalist:Total Wennovation Hackathon 2015.First Place:PIND Effurun Agric Hackathon 2016.

PERSONAL DETAILS:

Nationality: Nigerian.

Date of Birth: 7th December 1994. **Marital Status:** Single.

REFERENCES: Available on request.